<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hermit on Hermit Docs</title><link>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/</link><description>Recent content in Hermit on Hermit Docs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Get Started</title><link>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/usage/get-started/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/usage/get-started/</guid><description>This document gives a brief introduction to installing Hermit and using a newly created environment.
Installing Hermit Installing Hermit is straightforward:
curl -fsSL https://github.com/cashapp/hermit/releases/download/stable/install.sh | /bin/bash This will download and install hermit into ~/bin. You should add this to your $PATH if it isn't already.
Also consider installing the shell hooks to get automatic environment activation/deactivation when changing directories. Initialising a Project Change into a project directory and run the following:</description></item><item><title>Environment variables</title><link>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/usage/envars/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/usage/envars/</guid><description>When a Hermit environment is active, environment variables will be set by Hermit itself, the command-line, the active environment, and installed packages, in that order.
Hermit includes a hermit env command to view and set per-environment variables:
Usage: hermit env [&amp;lt;name&amp;gt;] [&amp;lt;value&amp;gt;] Manage environment variables. Without arguments the &amp;#34;env&amp;#34; command will display environment variables for the active Hermit environment. Passing &amp;#34;&amp;lt;name&amp;gt;&amp;#34; will print the value for that environment variable. Passing &amp;#34;&amp;lt;name&amp;gt; &amp;lt;value&amp;gt;&amp;#34; will set the value for an environment variable in the active Hermit environment.</description></item><item><title>Package management</title><link>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/usage/management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/usage/management/</guid><description>This document describes how packages within a Hermit environment can be found, installed, and managed. Packages are defined in configuration files called manifests which are retrieved from collections of manifests called manifest sources which in turn are commonly (but not always) Git repositories.
Keeping up to Date Hermit retrieves package manifests from various locations, including Git repositories. It will periodically sync these repositories to your system to ensure you have the most up to date manifests, but you may also force this by running:</description></item><item><title>Editor / IDE Integration</title><link>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/usage/ide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/usage/ide/</guid><description>Due to the way JetBrains IDE plugin APIs are designed, specific support for each language has to be built into the plugin. Currently only the JDK and Go are supported. Add the following URL to your IDE via the [Custom Plugin Repositories](https://www.jetbrains.com/help/idea/custom-plugin-repositories.html) dialog: ```text https://github.com/cashapp/hermit/releases/download/stable/updatePlugins.xml ``` Then search for the "Hermit" plugin and install it. You will need to restart your IDE. The plugin will automatically configure Go and Java SDKs to work with the IDE, including Run Configurations, tests, and the builtin terminal.</description></item><item><title>Shell Integration</title><link>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/usage/shell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/usage/shell/</guid><description>Tracking Environment Variables When a Hermit environment is activated, Hermit will install a shell hook to keep your shell's environment variables synchronised with Hermit's environment variables as you add and remove packages. This hook executes prior to each command.
Automatic Environment Activation / Deactivation Hermit can also install shell integration hooks to automate activation/deactivation of Hermit environments as you change directories in your terminal.</description></item><item><title>Configuration</title><link>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/usage/config/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/usage/config/</guid><description>Each Hermit environment contains a bin/hermit.hcl file that can be used to customise that Hermit environment.
Attributes Attribute Type Description env {string:string}? Extra environment variables. sources [string]? Package manifest sources in order of preference. manage-git bool? Whether Hermit should manage Git. Per-environment Sources Hermit supports three different manifest sources:
Git repositories; any cloneable URI ending with .</description></item><item><title>Continuous Integration</title><link>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/usage/ci/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/usage/ci/</guid><description>Generally, using Hermit in CI is similar to using it locally - activate your environment via . ./bin/activate-hermit, add &amp;lt;repo&amp;gt;/bin to your $PATH, or use ./bin/hermit env to directly update your CI environment.
GitHub Actions Using Hermit in GitHub Actions is straightforward. Just add the following step to each job:
- name:Init Hermitrun:./bin/hermit env &amp;gt;&amp;gt; $GITHUB_ENVeg.
jobs:test:name:Testruns-on:ubuntu-lateststeps:- name:Checkout codeuses:actions/checkout@v2- name:Init Hermitrun:./bin/hermit env &amp;gt;&amp;gt; $GITHUB_ENV- name:Testrun:go test .</description></item><item><title>Updating</title><link>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/usage/updates/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/usage/updates/</guid><description>Hermit is designed in such a way that it and its package manifests are always on the latest version. To that end, Hermit will check for and upgrade to new releases of itself once every 24 hours, and will sync to the latest package definitions every 24 hours. If you notice a pause when using Hermit, this is often the cause.
You can read more about the implications of this on package maintenance in the packaging introduction.</description></item><item><title>Tutorial</title><link>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/packaging/tutorial/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/packaging/tutorial/</guid><description>For this tutorial we're going to package up jq, a supremely useful tool for filtering and transforming JSON.
Writing package manifests for Hermit should be fairly familiar to anyone who has had experience with package managers like Homebrew, though it should be significantly more straightforward assuming the package provides cross-platform binaries for download.
This tutorial covers a fairly simple package definition, but more complex examples exist such as graalvm. Please refer to the hermit-packages repository for many more examples.</description></item><item><title>Reference</title><link>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/packaging/reference/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/packaging/reference/</guid><description>Update Policy Hermit syncs manifest sources every 24 hours from HEAD. Because any changes are then immediately reflected in active environments, care must be taken to maintain backwards compatibility.
In particular this means:
Never delete or rename versions. Take care when updating environment variables. And in general think carefully about what impact your change will have if it is applied to an active environment.
Manifests Hermit manifests (package definitions) are HCL configuration files defining where to download packages from and how to install them.</description></item><item><title>Private Packages</title><link>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/packaging/private/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/packaging/private/</guid><description>Custom Hermit Hermit has a configurable command-line entry point which can be useful if you need to use a custom HTTP client in order to access your private packages or manifest sources. See the hermit main package for an example of how this is used.
This can be used to specify a custom set of sources, and other configuration, for your org.
Private Channel If you ship your own version of Hermit you must choose a unique channel name (typically your oganisation's name), eg.</description></item><item><title>&lt;manifest>.hcl</title><link>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/packaging/schema/manifest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/packaging/schema/manifest/</guid><description>Each Hermit package manifest is a nested structure containing OS/architecture-specific configuration.
Blocks Block Description channel &amp;lt;name&amp;gt; { … } Definition of and configuration for an auto-update channel. darwin { … } Darwin-specific configuration. linux { … } Linux-specific configuration. on &amp;lt;event&amp;gt; { … } Triggers to run on lifecycle events. version &amp;lt;version&amp;gt; { … } Definition of and configuration for a specific version.</description></item><item><title>darwin</title><link>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/packaging/schema/darwin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/packaging/schema/darwin/</guid><description>Darwin-specific configuration.
Used by: channel linux &amp;lt;manifest&amp;gt; version
Blocks Block Description darwin { … } Darwin-specific configuration. linux { … } Linux-specific configuration. on &amp;lt;event&amp;gt; { … } Triggers to run on lifecycle events. Attributes Attribute Type Description apps [string]? Relative paths to Mac .</description></item><item><title>linux</title><link>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/packaging/schema/linux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/packaging/schema/linux/</guid><description>Linux-specific configuration.
Used by: channel darwin &amp;lt;manifest&amp;gt; version
Blocks Block Description darwin { … } Darwin-specific configuration. linux { … } Linux-specific configuration. on &amp;lt;event&amp;gt; { … } Triggers to run on lifecycle events. Attributes Attribute Type Description apps [string]? Relative paths to Mac .</description></item><item><title>channel &lt;name></title><link>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/packaging/schema/channel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/packaging/schema/channel/</guid><description>Definition of and configuration for an auto-update channel.
Used by: &amp;lt;manifest&amp;gt;
Blocks Block Description darwin { … } Darwin-specific configuration. linux { … } Linux-specific configuration. on &amp;lt;event&amp;gt; { … } Triggers to run on lifecycle events. Attributes Attribute Type Description apps [string]? Relative paths to Mac .</description></item><item><title>version &lt;version></title><link>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/packaging/schema/version/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/packaging/schema/version/</guid><description>Definition of and configuration for a specific version.
Used by: &amp;lt;manifest&amp;gt;
Blocks Block Description darwin { … } Darwin-specific configuration. linux { … } Linux-specific configuration. on &amp;lt;event&amp;gt; { … } Triggers to run on lifecycle events. Attributes Attribute Type Description apps [string]? Relative paths to Mac .</description></item><item><title>on &lt;event></title><link>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/packaging/schema/on/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/packaging/schema/on/</guid><description>Triggers to run on lifecycle events.
Used by: channel darwin linux &amp;lt;manifest&amp;gt; version
Blocks Block Description chmod { … } Change a files mode. copy { … } A file to copy when the event is triggered. message { … } Display a message to the user. rename { … } Rename a file. run { … } A command to run when the event is triggered.</description></item><item><title>on > chmod</title><link>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/packaging/schema/chmod/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/packaging/schema/chmod/</guid><description>Change a files mode.
Used by: on
Attributes Attribute Type Description file string File to set mode on. mode number File mode to set.</description></item><item><title>on > copy</title><link>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/packaging/schema/copy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/packaging/schema/copy/</guid><description>A file to copy when the event is triggered.
Used by: on
Attributes Attribute Type Description from string The source file to copy from. Absolute paths reference the file system while relative paths are against the manifest source bundle. to string The relative destination to copy to, based on the context.</description></item><item><title>on > message</title><link>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/packaging/schema/message/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/packaging/schema/message/</guid><description>Display a message to the user.
Used by: on
Attributes Attribute Type Description text string Message text to display to user.</description></item><item><title>on > rename</title><link>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/packaging/schema/rename/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/packaging/schema/rename/</guid><description>Rename a file.
Used by: on
Attributes Attribute Type Description from string Source path to rename. to string Destination path to rename to.</description></item><item><title>on > run</title><link>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/packaging/schema/run/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/packaging/schema/run/</guid><description>A command to run when the event is triggered.
Used by: on
Attributes Attribute Type Description args [string]? The arguments to the binary cmd string The command to execute dir string? The directory where the command is run in. Defaults to the root directory. env [string]? The environment variables for the execution stdin string?</description></item></channel></rss>