<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Usage on Hermit Docs</title><link>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/usage/</link><description>Recent content in Usage on Hermit Docs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/usage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Get Started</title><link>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/usage/get-started/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/usage/get-started/</guid><description>This document gives a brief introduction to installing Hermit and using a newly created environment.
Installing Hermit Installing Hermit is straightforward:
curl -fsSL https://github.com/cashapp/hermit/releases/download/stable/install.sh | /bin/bash This will download and install hermit into ~/bin. You should add this to your $PATH if it isn't already.
Also consider installing the shell hooks to get automatic environment activation/deactivation when changing directories. Initialising a Project Change into a project directory and run the following:</description></item><item><title>Environment variables</title><link>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/usage/envars/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/usage/envars/</guid><description>When a Hermit environment is active, environment variables will be set by Hermit itself, the command-line, the active environment, and installed packages, in that order.
Hermit includes a hermit env command to view and set per-environment variables:
Usage: hermit env [&amp;lt;name&amp;gt;] [&amp;lt;value&amp;gt;] Manage environment variables. Without arguments the &amp;#34;env&amp;#34; command will display environment variables for the active Hermit environment. Passing &amp;#34;&amp;lt;name&amp;gt;&amp;#34; will print the value for that environment variable. Passing &amp;#34;&amp;lt;name&amp;gt; &amp;lt;value&amp;gt;&amp;#34; will set the value for an environment variable in the active Hermit environment.</description></item><item><title>Package management</title><link>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/usage/management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/usage/management/</guid><description>This document describes how packages within a Hermit environment can be found, installed, and managed. Packages are defined in configuration files called manifests which are retrieved from collections of manifests called manifest sources which in turn are commonly (but not always) Git repositories.
Keeping up to Date Hermit retrieves package manifests from various locations, including Git repositories. It will periodically sync these repositories to your system to ensure you have the most up to date manifests, but you may also force this by running:</description></item><item><title>Editor / IDE Integration</title><link>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/usage/ide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/usage/ide/</guid><description>Due to the way JetBrains IDE plugin APIs are designed, specific support for each language has to be built into the plugin. Currently only the JDK and Go are supported. Add the following URL to your IDE via the [Custom Plugin Repositories](https://www.jetbrains.com/help/idea/custom-plugin-repositories.html) dialog: ```text https://github.com/cashapp/hermit/releases/download/stable/updatePlugins.xml ``` Then search for the "Hermit" plugin and install it. You will need to restart your IDE. The plugin will automatically configure Go and Java SDKs to work with the IDE, including Run Configurations, tests, and the builtin terminal.</description></item><item><title>Shell Integration</title><link>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/usage/shell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/usage/shell/</guid><description>Tracking Environment Variables When a Hermit environment is activated, Hermit will install a shell hook to keep your shell's environment variables synchronised with Hermit's environment variables as you add and remove packages. This hook executes prior to each command.
Automatic Environment Activation / Deactivation Hermit can also install shell integration hooks to automate activation/deactivation of Hermit environments as you change directories in your terminal.</description></item><item><title>Configuration</title><link>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/usage/config/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/usage/config/</guid><description>Each Hermit environment contains a bin/hermit.hcl file that can be used to customise that Hermit environment.
Attributes Attribute Type Description env {string:string}? Extra environment variables. sources [string]? Package manifest sources in order of preference. manage-git bool? Whether Hermit should manage Git. Per-environment Sources Hermit supports three different manifest sources:
Git repositories; any cloneable URI ending with .</description></item><item><title>Continuous Integration</title><link>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/usage/ci/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/usage/ci/</guid><description>Generally, using Hermit in CI is similar to using it locally - activate your environment via . ./bin/activate-hermit, add &amp;lt;repo&amp;gt;/bin to your $PATH, or use ./bin/hermit env to directly update your CI environment.
GitHub Actions Using Hermit in GitHub Actions is straightforward. Just add the following step to each job:
- name:Init Hermitrun:./bin/hermit env &amp;gt;&amp;gt; $GITHUB_ENVeg.
jobs:test:name:Testruns-on:ubuntu-lateststeps:- name:Checkout codeuses:actions/checkout@v2- name:Init Hermitrun:./bin/hermit env &amp;gt;&amp;gt; $GITHUB_ENV- name:Testrun:go test .</description></item><item><title>Updating</title><link>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/usage/updates/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cashapp.github.io/hermit/usage/updates/</guid><description>Hermit is designed in such a way that it and its package manifests are always on the latest version. To that end, Hermit will check for and upgrade to new releases of itself once every 24 hours, and will sync to the latest package definitions every 24 hours. If you notice a pause when using Hermit, this is often the cause.
You can read more about the implications of this on package maintenance in the packaging introduction.</description></item></channel></rss>